[
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66435499082c8d69eedbdbe9" },
    "front": "mühselig, müde",
    "back": "weary",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈwɪə.ri/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:55:22.411Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "Come to me, all you who are weary.",
    "exampleFront": "Kommt zu mir, ihr alle, die ihr müde seid.",
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:48:45.015Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664354f1082c8d69eedbdbeb" },
    "front": "ins Ausland",
    "back": "abroad",
    "pronunciation": "/əˈbroood/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:51:15.678Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "We usually go abroad for a week in May.",
    "exampleFront": "Normalerweise fahren wir im Mai für eine Woche ins Ausland.",
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:29.422Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66435552082c8d69eedbdbed" },
    "front": "Nachbarschaft, Umgebung",
    "back": "vicinity",
    "pronunciation": "/vɪˈsɪn.ə.ti/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-09-12T08:10:17.111Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "The number of people living in the immediate vicinity was small.",
    "exampleFront": "Die Zahl der in der unmittelbaren Umgebung lebenden Menschen war gering.",
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:14:16.776Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6643559f082c8d69eedbdbef" },
    "front": "verunreinigen, entehren",
    "back": "defile",
    "pronunciation": "/dɪˈfaɪl/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-09-12T08:14:50.715Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "The tomb has been defiled and looted.",
    "exampleFront": "Das Grab wurde geschändet und geplündert.",
    "rStatus": 3,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:14:25.571Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664355ed082c8d69eedbdbf1" },
    "front": "einsam, alleine",
    "back": "solitary",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈsɒl.ɪ.tr.i/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:36:18.223Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "When Jesus heard what had happened, he withdrew by boat privately to a solitary place.",
    "exampleFront": "Als Jesus hörte, was geschehen war, zog er sich mit dem Boot an einen einsamen Ort zurück.",
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66435632082c8d69eedbdbf3" },
    "front": "verklären",
    "back": "romanticize",
    "pronunciation": "/rəʊˈmæn.tɪ.saɪz/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:55:46.688Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "exampleBack": "We are romanticizing about the past.",
    "exampleFront": "Wir haben eine romantische Vorstellung von der Vergangenheit.",
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:49:42.132Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6644c9e46754967c4accc1cb" },
    "front": "bloß, nur",
    "exampleFront": "Ich habe mich nicht beschwert, ich habe nur gesagt, dass ich müde bin.",
    "back": "merely",
    "exampleBack": "I wasn't complaining, I merely said that I was tired.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈmɪə.li/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-09-12T08:09:27.848Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:15:46.021Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6645d5110bbf8c28c77c47b6" },
    "front": "verfallen, verlieren",
    "exampleFront": "Wenn Sie jetzt stornieren, verfällt Ihre Anzahlung.",
    "back": "forfeit",
    "exampleBack": "If you cancel now, you forfeit your deposit.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈfɔː.fɪt/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-08-31T07:36:47.155Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 4,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:36:08.287Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6645d63d0bbf8c28c77c47b8" },
    "front": "Besitzergreifung, Beschlagnahme",
    "exampleFront": "Beschlagnahme von Macht/Eigentum/Kontrolle",
    "back": "seizure n.",
    "exampleBack": "Seizure of power/property/control",
    "pronunciation": " /ˈsiː.ʒər/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:42:36.132Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:16:07.973Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6645d6a80bbf8c28c77c47ba" },
    "front": "\tjmdn. rügen, tadeln",
    "exampleFront": "Ich wurde von meinem Vorgesetzten zurechtgewiesen, weil ich zu spät kam.",
    "back": "rebuke",
    "exampleBack": "I was rebuked by my manager for being late.",
    "pronunciation": "/rɪˈbjuːk/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:51:47.403Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:49:53.052Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664728c70bbf8c28c77c47de" },
    "front": "Streit, Auseinandersetzung",
    "exampleFront": "Nach Angaben von Zeugen begann der Streit zwischen den beiden Männern im Inneren des Restaurants.",
    "back": "altercation",
    "exampleBack": "According to witnesses, the altercation between the two men started inside the restaurant.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌɒl.təˈkeɪ.ʃən/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-06T08:57:56.484Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-30T05:23:25.294Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664747ce0bbf8c28c77c47e2" },
    "front": "Neigung, Veranlagung",
    "exampleFront": "Sie hat eine lästige Veranlagung, Fehler zu finden.",
    "back": "predisposition",
    "exampleBack": "She has an annoying predisposition to find fault.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌpriː.dɪs.pəˈzɪʃ.ən/",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:12:45.691Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66477f7e0bbf8c28c77c47e4" },
    "front": "etw. vermeiden",
    "exampleFront": "Beschriften Sie Ihre Koffer, um Verwechslungen zu vermeiden.",
    "back": "prevent",
    "exampleBack": "Label your suitcases to prevent confusion.",
    "pronunciation": "/prɪˈvent/ ",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:34:48.789Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66477fd70bbf8c28c77c47e6" },
    "front": "Historiker",
    "exampleFront": "Einige Historiker glauben, dass sich die Geschichte wiederholt.",
    "back": "historian",
    "exampleBack": "Some historians think that history repeats itself.",
    "pronunciation": " /hɪˈstɔː.ri.ən/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T15:02:16.235Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:49:00.717Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664780910bbf8c28c77c47e8" },
    "front": "folgsam, gefügig",
    "exampleFront": "Die einst folgsame Bevölkerung hat sich schließlich gegen das rücksichtslose Regime erhoben.",
    "back": "docile",
    "exampleBack": "The once docile population has finally risen up against the ruthless regime.",
    "pronunciation": " /ˈdəʊ.saɪl/",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:10:28.242Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6647817c0bbf8c28c77c47ea" },
    "front": "fromm, keusch, zuechtig",
    "exampleFront": "In der Vergangenheit musste eine Frau keusch sein, um eine vernünftige Ehe zu führen.",
    "back": "chaste",
    "exampleBack": "In the past, a woman needed to be chaste to make a good marriage.",
    "pronunciation": "/tʃeɪst/",
    "status": 2,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:51:23.172Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664782000bbf8c28c77c47ec" },
    "front": "eine Ort erkunden, erforschen",
    "exampleFront": "Die beste Art, die Landschaft zu erkunden, ist zu Fuß.",
    "back": "explore",
    "exampleBack": "The best way to explore the countryside is on foot.",
    "pronunciation": " /ɪkˈsplɔːr/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T15:01:48.449Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:48:52.5Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664782850bbf8c28c77c47ef" },
    "front": "Hingabe, Engagement",
    "exampleFront": "Sie dankte den Mitarbeitern für ihr Engagement und ihren Enthusiasmus.",
    "back": "dedication",
    "exampleBack": "She thanked the staff for their dedication and enthusiasm.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌded.ɪˈkeɪ.ʃən/",
    "status": 2,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:51:46.933Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6647839f0bbf8c28c77c47f1" },
    "front": "Heide, heidnisch",
    "exampleFront": "Das Osterei hat sowohl heidnische als auch christliche Ursprünge.",
    "back": "pagan",
    "exampleBack": "The Easter egg has both pagan and Christian origins.",
    "pronunciation": " /ˈpeɪ.ɡən/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:52:26.821Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:51:00.768Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6648a31a0bbf8c28c77c483a" },
    "front": "Boshaftigkeit, Schlechtigkeit",
    "exampleFront": "Sie würden für ihre Schlechtigkeit bestraft werden.",
    "back": "wickedness",
    "exampleBack": "They would be punished for their wickedness.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈwɪk.ɪd.nəs/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-09-12T08:11:27.755Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 4,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:37:24.973Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6648a3b70bbf8c28c77c483c" },
    "front": "Lebenszweck, Lebensinhalt",
    "exampleFront": "Wie Sie Ihren Lebenszweck finden.",
    "back": "purpose in life",
    "exampleBack": "How to find your purpose in life.",
    "pronunciation": "",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:44:22.339Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 4,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:35:04.278Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6648a4750bbf8c28c77c483e" },
    "front": "Strategie, strategisch",
    "exampleFront": "Ihre Bomben werden immer an strategischen Stellen platziert, um so viel Chaos wie möglich zu verursachen.",
    "back": "strategic",
    "exampleBack": " Their bombs are always placed in strategic positions to cause as much chaos as possible.\n",
    "pronunciation": "/strəˈteː.dʒɪk/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-08-22T13:16:35.262Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 4,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:33:34.647Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6648a67b0bbf8c28c77c4840" },
    "front": "Genusssucht, Selbstverliebtheit ",
    "exampleFront": "Warum sollte man ihnen ein schlechtes Gewissen machen, wenn sie sich ein wenig selbst verwöhnen? ",
    "back": "self-indulgence",
    "exampleBack": "Why should they be made to feel guilty for a little self-indulgence? ",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌself.ɪnˈdʌ[a]l.dʒəns/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:44:49.897Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 4,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:37:40.088Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6648a71d0bbf8c28c77c4842" },
    "front": "Hörigkeit, Knechtschaft",
    "exampleFront": "Die Sklaven wurden bis zu ihrem Tod in Knechtschaft gehalten.",
    "back": "bondage",
    "exampleBack": "The slaves were kept in bondage until their death.",
    "pronunciation": " /ˈbɒn.dɪdʒ/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:49:14.502Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:51:14.837Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664a1a640bbf8c28c77c486c" },
    "front": "verschlafen",
    "exampleFront": "Ich habe heute Morgen den Bus verpasst, weil ich wieder verschlafen habe.",
    "back": "oversleep",
    "exampleBack": "I missed the bus this morning because I overslept again.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌəʊ.vəˈsliːp/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:53:18.815Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:06.808Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664a1b240bbf8c28c77c486e" },
    "front": "Umstand",
    "exampleFront": "Sie starb unter verdächtigen Umständen.",
    "back": "circumstance",
    "exampleBack": "She died in suspicious circumstances.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈsɜː.kəm.stɑːns/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:42:25.889Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-30T05:26:40.518Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664a1be00bbf8c28c77c4870" },
    "front": "einen Schock erleiden",
    "exampleFront": "Das könnte für alle ein Schock sein.",
    "back": "be in for a shock ",
    "exampleBack": "Everybody could be in for a shock.",
    "pronunciation": "",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:48:54.344Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:49:36.367Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b796e0bbf8c28c77c48a4" },
    "front": "Anspruch",
    "exampleFront": "Diese Arbeit liegt unter dem Standard.",
    "back": "standard",
    "exampleBack": "This piece of work is below standard.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈstæn.dəd/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:51:36.961Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:51:32.648Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b79e60bbf8c28c77c48a6" },
    "front": "treu ergeben, zugetan",
    "exampleFront": "Lucy ist ihren Katzen treu ergeben.",
    "back": "devoted",
    "exampleBack": "Lucy is devoted to her cats.",
    "pronunciation": "/dɪˈvəʊ.tɪd/",
    "status": 2,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:24.958Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b7a760bbf8c28c77c48a8" },
    "front": " erwägen, prüfen",
    "exampleFront": "Treffen Sie keine Entscheidungen, bevor Sie die Situation bedacht haben.",
    "back": "consider",
    "exampleBack": "Don't make any decisions before you've considered the situation.",
    "pronunciation": "/kənˈsɪd.ər/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:56:54.581Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:44.182Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b7abe0bbf8c28c77c48aa" },
    "front": "Vorfahren",
    "exampleFront": "An den Wänden des Raums hingen Porträts seiner Vorfahren.",
    "back": "ancestor",
    "exampleBack": "There were portraits of his ancestors on the walls of the room.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈæn.ses.tər/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:44:42.624Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-30T05:26:12.998Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b7b240bbf8c28c77c48ac" },
    "front": "Haltung, Einstellung",
    "exampleFront": "Die Haltung des Arztes zur Frage der Abtreibung ist bekannt.",
    "back": "stance",
    "exampleBack": "The doctor's stance on the issue of abortion is well known.",
    "pronunciation": "/stɑːns/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:33:50.284Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664b7b960bbf8c28c77c48ae" },
    "front": "Gier",
    "exampleFront": "Ich weiß nicht, warum ich mehr esse - es ist nicht Hunger, es ist einfach Gier!",
    "back": "greed",
    "exampleBack": "I don't know why I'm eating more - it's not hunger, it's just greed!",
    "pronunciation": "/ɡriːd/",
    "status": 2,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:54.678Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664ddc43dc17e188aa5f10f4" },
    "front": "Nachkomme",
    "exampleFront": "Nachkomme von vier Großeltern",
    "back": "descendant",
    "exampleBack": "descendant of four grandparents",
    "pronunciation": "/dɪˈsen.dənt/",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:11:21.026Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "664de5b1dc17e188aa5f10f6" },
    "front": "Ureinwohner, Einheimische",
    "exampleFront": "Wer sind also die Ureinwohner dieses Landes?",
    "back": "indigenous",
    "exampleBack": "So who are the indigenous people of this land?",
    "pronunciation": "/ɪnˈdɪdʒ.ɪ.nəs/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:43:49.353Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:12:35.921Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f17f0bbf8c28c77c49fe" },
    "front": "prüde, zimperlich",
    "exampleFront": "Sei nicht so prüde.",
    "back": "prude",
    "exampleBack": "Don't be such a prude.",
    "pronunciation": "/pruːd/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-07-16T14:41:55.998Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:14:11.705Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f2fe0bbf8c28c77c4a00" },
    "front": "unterdrücken",
    "exampleFront": "Er hat seinen Groll jahrelang unterdrückt.",
    "back": "suppress",
    "exampleBack": "His feelings of resentment have been suppressed for years.",
    "pronunciation": " /səˈpres/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:33:56.907Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f4120bbf8c28c77c4a02" },
    "front": "überliefern",
    "exampleFront": "Das Schreiben wurde lange Zeit mündlich überliefert.",
    "back": "to hand smth. down",
    "exampleBack": "The letter was handed down orally for a long time.",
    "pronunciation": "",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-30T05:24:23.777Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f4c90bbf8c28c77c4a04" },
    "front": "übergriffig, aufdringlich",
    "exampleFront": "Einige der Fragen des Interviewers empfand sie als aufdringlich.",
    "back": "intrusive",
    "exampleBack": "She found some of the interviewer's questions intrusive.",
    "pronunciation": "/ɪnˈtruː.sɪv/",
    "status": 1,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-25T05:49:11.039Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f5330bbf8c28c77c4a06" },
    "front": "unsensibel",
    "exampleFront": "Die Polizei wurde dafür kritisiert, dass sie gegenüber Beschwerden aus der Öffentlichkeit unsensibel ist.",
    "back": "insensitive",
    "exampleBack": "The police have been criticized for being insensitive to complaints from the public.",
    "pronunciation": "/ɪnˈsen.sɪ.tɪv/",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-30T05:27:11.082Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6655f6d80bbf8c28c77c4a08" },
    "front": "mit den Zähnen knirschen",
    "exampleFront": "Über den Vorschlag, das Krankenhaus zu schließen, wurde heftig mit den Zähnen geknirscht.",
    "back": "gnashing of teeth",
    "exampleBack": "There has been much gnashing of teeth about the proposal to close the hospital.",
    "pronunciation": "",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:10:06.697Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "666005380bbf8c28c77c4a93" },
    "front": "sich erinnern",
    "exampleFront": "„Wenn ich mich recht erinnere“, sagte er etwas gereizt, „schulden Sie mir noch 150 €.“",
    "back": "recall",
    "exampleBack": "\"As I recall,\" he said with some irritation, \"you still owe me €150.\"",
    "pronunciation": "/rɪˈkɔːl/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:35:25.652Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "666005fb0bbf8c28c77c4a95" },
    "front": "Theologe",
    "exampleFront": "",
    "back": "theologian",
    "exampleBack": "",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌθiː.əˈləʊ.dʒən/ ",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:33:27.017Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "6660072e0bbf8c28c77c4a97" },
    "front": "Bräutigam",
    "exampleFront": "",
    "back": "bridegroom",
    "exampleBack": "",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈbraɪd.ɡruːm/ ",
    "status": 3,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:11:50.671Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "666007ac0bbf8c28c77c4a99" },
    "front": "bekannt, berühmt",
    "exampleFront": "Die Region ist bekannt für ihre außergewöhnliche natürliche Schönheit.",
    "back": "renowned",
    "exampleBack": "The region is renowned for its outstanding natural beauty.",
    "pronunciation": " /rɪˈnaʊnd/   au",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-08-01T17:17:51.247Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 5,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:14:35.256Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc2c80bbf8c28c77c4b42" },
    "front": "Wesen, Naturell",
    "exampleFront": "Sie ist sehr temperamentvoll.",
    "back": "temper",
    "exampleBack": "She has a real temper.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈtem.pər/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-09T06:15:39.386Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc35f0bbf8c28c77c4b44" },
    "front": "zufrieden",
    "exampleFront": "Sie lächelte ein zufriedenes Lächeln.",
    "back": "contented",
    "exampleBack": "She smiled a contented smile.",
    "pronunciation": "/kənˈten.tɪd/",
    "status": 2,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-26T06:15:25.511Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc3a50bbf8c28c77c4b46" },
    "front": "rücksichtsvoll",
    "exampleFront": "Es war nicht sehr rücksichtsvoll von dir, die ganze Milch zu trinken.",
    "back": "considerate",
    "exampleBack": "It wasn't very considerate of you to drink all the milk.",
    "pronunciation": "/kənˈsɪd.ər.ət/",
    "status": 3,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:14:31.081Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc3ef0bbf8c28c77c4b48" },
    "front": "Vorurteil",
    "exampleFront": "Die Gesetze gegen Rassenvorurteile müssen strikt durchgesetzt werden.",
    "back": "prejudice",
    "exampleBack": "Laws against racial prejudice must be strictly enforced.",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈpredʒ.ə.dɪs/",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:12:11.251Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc4430bbf8c28c77c4b4a" },
    "front": "unfähig",
    "exampleFront": "Ich bin hoffnungslos unfähig, Dinge zu reparieren.",
    "back": "inefficient",
    "exampleBack": "I'm hopelessly inefficient at fixing things.",
    "pronunciation": " /ˌɪn.ɪˈfɪʃ.ənt/",
    "status": 3,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:10:33.517Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc49f0bbf8c28c77c4b4c" },
    "front": "unaufrichtig",
    "exampleFront": "eine unaufrichtige Entschuldigung",
    "back": "insincere",
    "exampleBack": "an insincere apology",
    "pronunciation": "/ˌɪn.sɪnˈsɪər/ ",
    "status": 5,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-11-21T06:10:00.978Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc5110bbf8c28c77c4b4e" },
    "front": "entgegenkommend",
    "exampleFront": "Er war ein äußerst entgegenkommender  Zeuge.",
    "back": "cooperative",
    "exampleBack": "He was an extremely co-operative witness.",
    "pronunciation": "/kəʊˈɒp.ər.ə.tɪv/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:54:39.806Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-24T05:52:01.583Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc5810bbf8c28c77c4b50" },
    "front": "gehemmt, ungehemmt",
    "exampleFront": "Durch die Anwesenheit von Fremden fühlte sie sich gehemmt.",
    "back": "inhibited, uninhibited",
    "exampleBack": "The presence of strangers made her feel inhibited.",
    "pronunciation": " /ɪnˈhɪb.ɪ.tɪd/",
    "status": 4,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:37:04.169Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-07-23T13:13:01.906Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "667fc5d70bbf8c28c77c4b53" },
    "front": "angenehme",
    "exampleFront": "ein angenehmer Tag/eine angenehme Überraschung",
    "back": "pleasant",
    "exampleBack": "a pleasant day/surprise",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈplez.ənt/",
    "status": 6,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-11T14:59:26.644Z" },
    "__v": 0,
    "rStatus": 2,
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-28T05:50:01.579Z" }
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66ff7dc8d5965e735766dace" },
    "front": "das Becken",
    "exampleFront": "Jedes Bein hat ein Becken-, ein Knie- und zwei Fußgelenke. ",
    "back": "pelvis",
    "exampleBack": "Each leg has a pelvis, knee and two ankle joints. ",
    "pronunciation": "/ˈpɛlvɪs/",
    "status": 3,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:16:22.313Z" },
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-04T05:31:52.595Z" },
    "__v": 0
  },
  {
    "_id": { "$oid": "66ff7e5ed5965e735766dad0" },
    "front": "Rumpf ( anat. )",
    "exampleFront": "",
    "back": "trunk ( anat. )",
    "exampleBack": "",
    "pronunciation": " /trʌŋk/",
    "status": 3,
    "rStatus": 0,
    "user": { "$oid": "6639de7548b6b4e4efdc56ff" },
    "date": { "$date": "2024-10-29T06:10:49.332Z" },
    "rDate": { "$date": "2024-10-04T05:34:22.918Z" },
    "__v": 0
  }
]
